MUHAMMAD AQSAM

maqsam • MoAqsam

EDUCATION

SUMMARY

Seneca College (2017-2019)

Diploma Computer Programming Excellent academic standing with a 3.6/4.0 GPA. Software Developer with over 1 year experience in coding, testing and developing web, mobile applications and web service's through various internships/co-op placements and working at a start-up.

SKILLS

SOFT-SKILLS: Effective and clear communicator, punctual and efficient, excellent problem solver, effective time management, creative and self-confident, excellent team worker, strong work ethic, strong analytical thinking.

TECHNICAL-SKILLS: Java, Python. DATABASE: MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

WEB DEV: JavaScript, TypeScript, ECMA 6, Angular(2+), ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, HTML(5), CSS(3), Jquery, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS.

EMPLOYMENT

Ontario Ministry of Health and Long-Term Care (Co-op), Application Developer, 415 Yonge Street, Toronto, M5B 2E7

Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- · Helped develop a application to modernize the view of assessments using SpringBoot, Java, Bootstrap and thymaleaf.
- Documented and tested applications and API's using SoapUI and Groovy script.
- Provided support to existing applications.

Vision Loop LTD, Team Lead - Full Stack Developer

July 2018 - February 2019

Developing a mobile and web application at a startup for car wrap services.

- Developed API's using NodeJS, Express framework and MongoDB.
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens for authentication and to protect API routes.
- Used Ionic/Angular framework on the front-end to design and populate pages with data from API.
- Used encryption algorithms to encrypt bank information and bcrypt to hash passwords.
- Developed Website using ReactJS and connected backend to Supwrap API.

Workers Safety Insurance Board (internship), Application Developer, 200 Front Street West Toronto, ON M5V 3J1

Jan. 2018 - Apr. 2018

- Developed and implemented branded SharePoint websites for internal branches.
- Extensive documentation of core applications and user manuals for SharePoint websites and content management of sites.
- Developed project sites for SharePoint team and provided support to existing SharePoint applications.

PROJECTS

Supwrap website - ReactJS

- Developed website using ReactJS, Redux and MaterializeCSS.
- Designed the UI and connected it to back-end.
- Implemented Redux to manage state of application.

Supwrap mobile app - Ionic/Angular

- Developed back-end API for Supwrap mobile app using NodeJS, ExpressJS, and Mongoose.
- Used Ionic/Angular with Cordova to assist in developing IOS/Android front-end and connecting it to the API.
- Implemented security best practices for sensitive transactions.

Job Tracker - ReactJS

- Created a open source project using ReactJS to track job applications.
- Used bootstrap to make web app responsive.
- · Application deployed on github.

Cell City - Website

- Developed a modern and responsive website for a client.
- Used advance techniques in HTML(5) and CSS(3) with FlexBoxGrid framework.
- Designed and developed site to be cross-platform and responsive with easy user interface and sleek design.

ACTIVITIES

- Enjoy learning new technologies and reading about history.
- Love playing basketball, hockey, and football.